caspio.com 2014-07-13

# Caspio Privacy Statement

## For Website Users and Clients

Last modified April 15, 2014.

### OVERVIEW

Caspio, Inc. is committed to respecting your privacy and the privacy of the information in your account. That is why we have established this Privacy Statement. Our intention is to treat your information with utmost care and consideration. If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should contact Caspio as outlined below.

We want you to know that we are not in the business of selling or renting individuals' personal data to other companies for any purpose.

Caspio, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/index.html "TRUSTe Program Requirements") including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover downloadable software and only covers caspio.com websites.  TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. Please direct all your inquiries pertaining to the Site, Service, or this Statement to us by contacting Caspio. In the event your inquiry isn't acknowledged within a reasonable time expectation, or hasn't been addressed to your satisfaction, please [contact TRUSTe](http://www.truste.com/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php). TRUSTe shall then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns.

Caspio complies with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries and Switzerland.  Caspio has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Caspio's certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

### COLLECTION AND USE OF YOUR INFORMATION

Caspio collects personally identifiable information when you register for a Caspio service account, when you sign up to become a Caspio affiliate, when you sign up to become a Caspio reseller, when you fill out any form requesting information, support, or product and service information, and when you subscribe to our news. Caspio may also receive personally identifiable information from its business partners.

Caspio collects the following personally identifiable information: your name, title, phone number, email address, mailing address, website URL, employer or company. You also have the option of supplying us with your occupation, and type of business or industry. Additionally, when you sign up for a Caspio paid service, we collect your billing information, including your credit card number, expiration date, and billing address.

Caspio also asks its affiliates and resellers to provide either their Tax ID or Social Security Number so we can comply with IRS regulations in regards to commissions and payments.

Caspio also automatically receives and records information on our server logs from your browser including your IP address, browser type, referrer page, domain name, access time, entry page, exit page, operating system type, and search engine keywords used.

We mainly use the information we collect to measure our business success, to identify the most effective ways to reach you, the customer, to more effectively meet your needs and requests for certain new product features and services, and to contact you about product upgrades. Additionally, if you have chosen to receive email communications, you will receive our infrequent news and announcements.

### DATA HOSTED BY CASPIO

Caspio hosts the data stored in your Caspio account. That data is strictly your property and is governed by the Terms of Service agreement of the service you have subscribed to. The data in your account is not accessible to anyone, unless you make it accessible.

### DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION ABOUT YOU

Certain Caspio employees have various access levels to Caspio systems, including databases, for the purposes of support, backups, maintenance, debugging, and other administrative and programming activities. However, Caspio will not monitor, edit, disclose, sell, or rent neither the data stored in your Caspio account, nor your personally identifiable information to anyone other than what is disclosed below. It is only under the following circumstances that we may send your information to other companies or people:

  1. When we have your consent to share the information.
  2. Disrupt the performance of Caspio servers or cause server-wide outages.
  3. When we need to share your information to provide you with a service or product you are requesting. For example: if you sign up for Caspio service through one of our authorized resellers.
  4. When we need to send the information to companies that work on our behalf to process an order you have made, or so they can provide a product or service to you. Note that these companies are not allowed to use your information for any reason other than to support us in assisting you. We employ the services of third-party payment processors to complete the payment fulfillment process for purchases made on the Site.
  5. When we conform to edicts of the law, to respond to subpoenas, court orders, or legal processes.
  6. When you have violated our Terms of Service Agreement for the service you are using or have used.
  7. When we act under exigent circumstances to protect the personal safety of our customers or the public.
  8. When we need to protect and defend the rights or property of Caspio.
  9. From time to time we may share aggregate data about our customers with other companies. In such cases no personally identifiable data will be made available to third parties.
  10. By using our website and our services and providing us with your personal data, you consent to this transfer of your personal data.

### CHILDREN AND PRIVACY

Our website does not offer information intended to attract children. We do not knowingly solicit personal information from children under the age of 13.

### COOKIES

Cookies are identifiers usually sent through your browser to reside temporarily or permanently on your computer's hard drive. The Caspio website and Caspio services use cookies tied to personally identifiable information for their operation. Certain services and functionalities will not work if you disable cookie functions on your browser.

Google Analytics uses a first-party cookie and JavaScript code to collect information about visitors to Caspio websites. Google Analytics anonymously tracks how our visitors interact with this website, including where they came from, what they did on the site, and whether they completed any transactions on the site such as news registration.

### "EMAIL-THIS-PAGE"

We may encourage our customers and website visitors to email pages of our website to themselves or to their friends, or tell a friend about Caspio products, services or events. If a customer or visitor chooses to email a page or refer a friend to us, we will use that information only for the purposes of sending Caspio-related information once, or as many times as you request. The email address will be stored in a database but we make no further contact and will only use it in aggregate format and for reporting purposes.

### LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES

Our website contains links to information on other websites. We do not have any control over these other websites, and therefore we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information that you provide while visiting those sites. Those sites are not governed by this Privacy Statement, and if you have questions about how a site uses your information, consult that site's privacy statement. Your friend may contact us to request that we remove this information from our database.

### SOCIAL MEDIA FEATURES AND WIDGETS

Our web site includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the ShareThis button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our web site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### CHANGING OR DELETING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

At any time, Caspio allows you to change or delete inaccuracies in the personally identifiable information you provided when signing up for Caspio service. In order to change or delete inaccuracies in your information, log into your account and select the Account Information option. If the options provided do not fully meet your needs, please contact us. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

### DATA RETENTION

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services.  We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### SECURITY

For both security and privacy purposes, your Caspio account is password-protected.

Caspio employs rigid security measure, including restricting physical access to Caspio servers, to ensure the protection of your data and applications.

All communications between your account and Caspio servers are encrypted with an industry-standard Secure Socket Layers protocol, and your own applications and DataPages can be deployed securely using SSL at no extra charge.

Additionally, all systems are backed up on a daily basis.

### YOUR CONSENT

By using our website and services, you consent to the collection and use of the information you provide to us as outlined in this Privacy Statement. We may change this Privacy Statement from time to time and without notice. If we change our Privacy Statement, we will publish those changes on this page.

### OPTING-OUT

At any time you can unsubscribe from our news and announcement list by accessing our http://www.caspio.com/unsubscribe.aspx. If you have a Caspio account, you will continue to receive administrative type emails from us in regards to your account when necessary.

### SURVEYS

From time to time Caspio may invite you to participate in online surveys that Caspio or a third party may administer. These surveys are optional. These surveys include personal information such as name and email. They include questions about your experience with Caspio services and their specific features. They are meant to help us better understand the needs and requirements of our customers so we can continue improving our products and services. The results of these surveys may be shared in aggregate format with third parties.

### DEACTIVATING YOUR ACCOUNT

To deactivate your account, contact Caspio Support.

### TESTIMONIALS

From time to time, we post customer testimonials on the Site that may include their name, logo, graphic, sound or image. We obtain customer consent prior to posting their testimonials on the site. We are not responsible for the personal information a user elects to disclose in their testimonial. When users' elect to register their information to communicate in our forums, please be advised we're not responsible for the personal information users elect to share over this public platform. Please be advised any personal information disclosed can be used to send you unsolicited messages by other members of this forum.

### BLOGS AND FORUMS

Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, please contact us. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### LIVE CHAT

We provide real time live chat capabilities on the Site through a third party agent. When offline, the chat services records your inquiry which requires disclosure of your email to facilitate a response to you; this personal information is not used for promotional purposes.

### MATERIAL CHANGES

We reserve the right to make changes to this statement at our discretion. Should we make material changes to the manner in which your collected personal information is utilized, we shall post a prominent notice on the Site, or notify you by email of the change and your choices prior to the change becoming effective.

### OUR PRIVACY PRINCIPLES

Because your trust and confidence is important to us, Caspio conducts its Caspio services under the following privacy principles:

### CASPIO ACTS AS AN AGENT FOR OUR CUSTOMERS

Caspio acts as an Agent for each of our Customers, in that we provide our services solely for the benefit of the customer. Each of our customers uses Caspio services to collect data, or to provide information to their websites visitors; they use our services to create and operate database-powered web forms and applications. Each customer instructs us as to what types of data it would like us to collect on its behalf. This data may include the information you explicitly enter in web forms including personally identifiable information, or data implicitly collected through visiting a webpage or logging in to a password-protected area. We also collect certain technical information, such as the browser version and operating system. In each customer agreement, we promise that we will not make use of any data that we collect on the customer's behalf except as necessary to provide our services to that customer. We do not aggregate, sell, transfer, or otherwise disclose it to anyone but the customer, or pursuant to the customer's instructions. We do, however, reserve a limited right to disclose any data we collect if required by law or valid order of a court or other governmental authority.

### OUR CUSTOMERS' USE OF CASPIO SERVICES

We ask each of our customers to abide by all applicable laws, rules and regulations, as we promise our clients that we will do ourselves. We also recommend that each customer obtain all necessary consents from visitors to its website(s), post an online privacy policy that provides each visitor with notice of its data collection and use practices (including the customer's use of Caspio's services), and provide a link to the Caspio's privacy policy.

### USE OF COOKIES AND OTHER DATA COLLECTION METHODS

In providing services to our customers, it is Caspio's policy to use cookies only when necessary to maintain the identity of the user in a given session. The cookie information does not include personal data such as name, age, phone number, e-mail address or mailing address. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you would prefer, you can set your browser to reject cookies, however this may interfere with your usage of some of the services offered by Caspio's customers. Caspio's customers use customized JavaScript code provided by Caspio to contact Caspio's servers, to receive a form or application, to load an image or content, or to submit and update information.

### COMMENTS AND SUGGESTIONS

To contact us regarding this Privacy Statement, contact us on the Caspio.com website.
